John Perry Papers MS257
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
John Perry Papers
circa 1951 -- 2014
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Perry, John Curtis
MS257
3.4 Linear Feet
This collection contains the papers of John Curtis Perry, professor of East Asian and Maritime Studies at Tufts University from 1980 to 2015 and founder of both the North Pacific Program and the Maritime Studies Program at Tufts University. The collection includes correspondence, reports, maps, and other materials.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Perry, 2018, accession number MS-2019-042.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series.
Biographical / Historical
John Curtis Perry (1930-) was the Henry Willard Denison Professor of History at Tufts University's Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy from 1980 to 2015. He focused on East Asian and Maritime Studies during his career.
John Perry was born on July 18, 1930 in Orange, New Jersey. He grew up near Washington, D.C. and in New York, where he graduated from the Friends Seminary School. Due to his proximity to the capital during his childhood, Perry was able to work as a messenger boy for the Chinese embassy. He attended Yale University, where he received a Bachelor of Arts in Chinese Studies in 1952 and a Master of Arts in Foreign Area Studies. After serving in the US Army in Japan in the 1950s, Perry pursued his PhD in history at Harvard University, earning it in 1962.
Perry began his teaching career at Connecticut College in 1962. In 1966, he was offered a position at Carleton College in Minnesota, where he remained until he was offered a research fellowship at Harvard from 1976 until 1980. After this return to the Boston area, he accepted a position at Tufts University's Fletcher School in 1980, where he remained until his retirement in 2015.
In 1985, he founded the North Pacific Program, which brought ten to fifteen students from Tufts to some part of the North Pacific, usually Eastern Asia, for a yearly summer seminar. This program brought together students from Mexico, the United States, Canada, the Korean peninsula, China, Japan, and the Soviet Union/Russia for lectures and seminars, which prompted students to discuss "the cultural, economic and political trends of the participating countries" throughout history. In 1991, Perry received an imperial decoration, the Order of the Sacred Treasure, from the Japanese Government for his work with Japanese-American relations.
In 2000, the John Curtis Perry Fellowship was established to aid one Fletcher student with an interest in East Asian studies and policy. Colleagues and alumni, created the fellowship fund in Perry's honor and encouraged others to donate.
In addition to his work at Tufts, Perry also founded the Institute for Global Maritime Studies, a publicly supported educational non-profit. According to their website, one of the organization's responsibilities is to "research the various roles of the ocean as an avenue for the flow of goods, people and ideas; as an arena for combat and struggle; as a source of foodstuffs, energy, and minerals; and as a stimulus for creativity and recreation." Perry has served as a board member for the organization since its foundation in 2008.
In 1957, Perry married Sarah Hollis French. As of 2019, they have five children and ten grandchildren.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of John Curtis Perry, a professor of East Asian and Maritime Studies at Tufts University from 1980 to 2015. He founded both the North Pacific Program, which ran from 1985 – 1997, and the Maritime Studies Program at Tufts University. The Maritime Studies Program is documented in this collection, as are his many connections to students and colleagues from East Asia and the United States, formed during the North Pacific Program or by his own research interests. Independently of the two programs, Perry traveled frequently to East Asia both for personal reasons and for research, trips are detailed in this collection by correspondence and travel arrangements. This collection also contains the records for visiting researchers and lecturers from the North Pacific. As a leader in the field of East Asian Studies, Perry's papers include drafts and correspondence regarding his published works and his reviews of other books in the field. Materials date from the 1950s through the 2010s.
Faculty papers
- John Perry papers, 1951 -- 2014; MS257.001; 3.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the papers of John Curtis Perry, a professor of East Asian and Maritime Studies at Tufts University from 1980 to2015. He founded both the North Pacific Program, which ran from 1985 – 1997, and the Maritime Studies Program at Tufts University. The Maritime Studies Program is documented in this collection, as are his many connections to students and colleagues from East Asia and the United States, formed during the North Pacific Program or by his own research interests. Independently of the two programs, Perry traveled frequently to East Asia both for personal reasons and for research, trips are detailed in this collection by correspondence and travel arrangements. This collection also contains the records for visiting researchers and lecturers from the North Pacific. As a leader in the field of East Asian Studies, Perry's papers include drafts and correspondence regarding his published works and his reviews of other books in the field. Materials date from the 1950s through the 2010s.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  - Japan trip, 2011; MS257.001.001.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Open for research.
  - Harper and Row, 1981 -- 1984; MS257.001.001.00002; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - File misc of interest, 1985 -- 1989; MS257.001.001.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Punditry, 1985 -- 2008; MS257.001.001.00004; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Apollo, circa 1980s -- 2000s; MS257.001.001.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Russia reading materials, 1988 -- 1990; MS257.001.001.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foreign policy correspondence, 1989 -- 1991; MS257.001.001.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual report, 1998 -- 2014; MS257.001.001.00008; 4 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
  - Japan, 1999; MS257.001.001.00009; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Abu Dhabi, 2006 -- 2011; MS257.001.001.00010; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Kent Calder, 1983; MS257.001.001.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Naohiro Amaya visit, 1982-02; MS257.001.001.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - IFPA conference, 1982-06; MS257.001.001.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Pacific Security Ditchley Foundation Conference, 1985; MS257.001.001.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Spain, 2002; MS257.001.001.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Tokyo, 2000-02; MS257.001.001.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fletcher IGMS Norway tour, 2013-08; MS257.001.001.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Japan, 1994-03; MS257.001.001.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Paris Moscow, 1993-12; MS257.001.001.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Trip TYO SEL, 1992-12; MS257.001.001.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Travel notes Korea and Japan, 1986-10; MS257.001.001.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Trip to Japan, Thailand, Saudi Arabia, 1986-03; MS257.001.001.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Round the world trip, 1985; MS257.001.001.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Matsushita, 1982 -- 1983; MS257.001.001.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1985 -- 1986; MS257.001.001.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Japan, Korea, Singapore trip, 1985; MS257.001.001.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Korea and Japan trip, 1981; MS257.001.001.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Trip to East Asia, 1984-03; MS257.001.001.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Yonsei lecture notes, 1984-03; MS257.001.001.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Japan and Korea, 1997; MS257.001.001.00030; 3 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
  - Japan, 1983-08; MS257.001.001.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Korea, 1983-04; MS257.001.001.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Japan Mar-Apr 1983, 1983 -- 1983; MS257.001.001.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Japan October 1982, 1982-10; MS257.001.001.00034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Dec 1990 trip MOW, SEL, TYO, 1990-12; MS257.001.001.00035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - April 1990 trip, 1990-04; MS257.001.001.00036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Trips 1991, MS257.001.001.00037; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Korea and Japan, 1984 -- 1988; MS257.001.001.00038; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Rudy Jaafar, circa 2005; MS257.001.001.00039; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Starr Foundation, 1985 -- 1986; MS257.001.001.00040; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1997; MS257.001.001.00041; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Virginia Belsford Belyaev, circa 1990s -- 2000s; MS257.001.001.00042; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Ph.D.s, 1994 -- 2003; MS257.001.001.00043; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 52-53)
  - Japan and US symposium, 1986; MS257.001.001.00044; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Book reviews, 1968 -- 1993; MS257.001.001.00045; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
  - John D. Rockefeller 4th, 1953 -- 1954; MS257.001.001.00046; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - NAR and Japan, 1951 -- 1957; MS257.001.001.00047; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Development general, 2001 -- 2004; MS257.001.001.00048; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
  - Devel. Committee, 2004; MS257.001.001.00049; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Japan students' correspondence, 2006 -- 2011; MS257.001.001.00050; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 62-63)
  - Spain, 2001 -- 2002; MS257.001.001.00051; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 64)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Hist 270 US and Northeast Asia, 1999; MS257.001.001.00052; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Fletcher student bios, 2001 -- 2004; MS257.001.001.00053; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - General correspondence, 1981 -- 1982; MS257.001.002.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chronological file of John C. Perry correspondence, 1982; MS257.001.002.00002; 7 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 2-8)
  - Chronological file of John C. Perry correspondence, 1985; MS257.001.002.00003; 7 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 9-15)
  - Tokyo trip, 2001-11; MS257.001.002.00004; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Tokyo and Seoul trip, 2001-11; MS257.001.002.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Sevilla Seminar, 2001; MS257.001.002.00006; 3 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
  - U.S. and Japan Foundation, 1983 -- 1986; MS257.001.002.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Student comments on Japan seminar, 1984; MS257.001.002.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chronological file John C. Perry correspondence, 1986; MS257.001.002.00009; 7 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 25-31)
  - Chronological file JCP correspondence, 1981; MS257.001.002.00010; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - John Curtis Perry invoice and service agreement, 2007; MS257.001.002.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1984 -- 1992; MS257.001.002.00012; 3 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
  - Japan trip, 1981; MS257.001.002.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fletcher School student data cards, 1982 -- 1988; MS257.001.002.00014; 3 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
  - Kim Koo Symposium Busan and TYO, 2005; MS257.001.002.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Chronological file John C. Perry, 1984; MS257.001.002.00016; 6 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 43-48)
  - Courses 1990s, circa 1990s; MS257.001.003.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Maritime Studies Prog, 2007; MS257.001.003.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Other MS programs, 2007 -- 2008; MS257.001.003.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - JCP misc of interest, 1980 -- 1981; MS257.001.003.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Articles by John Curtis Perry, 1987 -- 1990; MS257.001.003.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "America's Deep Blue Highway" report, 2008; MS257.001.003.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Korea chair, 2004 -- 2006; MS257.001.003.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations, 1980 -- 1983; MS257.001.003.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Taiwan National Chengchi University, 1985 -- 1986; MS257.001.003.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Taiwan students at Fletcher, 1986 -- 1987; MS257.001.003.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Talloires Conference, 1985 -- 1986; MS257.001.003.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The New World of the North Pacific, 1986 -- 1996; MS257.001.003.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Japan Development Bank, 1991; MS257.001.003.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1985 -- 1997; MS257.001.003.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - World War I, 1984; MS257.001.003.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fletcher fundraising, 2001; MS257.001.003.00016; 2 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Advisees, 1989 -- 2003; MS257.001.003.00017; 2 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - General correspondence, 1996 -- 2007; MS257.001.003.00018; 2 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Face of China, 2001; MS257.001.003.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Asahi Shimbun, 1990 -- 1996; MS257.001.004.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Russia and East Asia, 2001; MS257.001.004.00002; 2 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Maps, circa 1990s; MS257.001.004.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Alaska, 1987 -- 1991; MS257.001.004.00004; 2 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Chronological file John C. Perry, 1983; MS257.001.004.00005; 6 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 8-13)